Register of the Franklin Lindsay papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1944-1958, 1976 (Box 8-9)
  - American Mission for Aid to Greece (AMAG) (Box 8)
    - "Preliminary Exchange of Notes between U.S. and Greek Governments on Greek Aid Program," correspondence, 1947 May 26-June 18; Mimeographed copy. (Box 8)
    - "Reconstruction Budget,", 1947 November 6; Typescript (photocopy). (Box 8)
    - "Report of the Economic Adviser and Director of the Public Finance Division," by Eugene H. Clay, memorandum, 1947 September 22; Two typescripts (carbon copies). (Box 8)
    - "Report of the Economic Adviser of the American Mission for Aid to Greece on the Economic and Financial Condition of Greece," memorandum, 1947 December 1; Mimeographed copy. (Box 8)
    - "Statement Concerning Civil Government Division," memorandum, undated; Typescript and carbon copy. (Box 8)
    - "Tentative Report of the American Economic Mission to Greece," report, 1947 April 25; Mimeographed copy. (Box 8)
      - Part I (Box 8)
      - Part II (Box 8)
    - "United States Post-War Aid to Greece," by Lindsay, 1947 December 11; Typescript (carbon copy). (Box 8)
    - Miscellany (Box 8)
  - European Management Group (Box 8)
    - List of names (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (Box 8)
    - Memoranda of conversations (Box 8)
    - Proposals (Box 8)
      - "Economic Unification of Western Europe," by Lindsay, four drafts, 1947 May; Typescript and carbon copies. (Box 8)
      - "Organization of a Managerial Group for European Reconstruction," by Lindsay, 1947 May 16 and June; Typescript and carbon copy. (Box 8)
      - "Technical and Managerial Functions," by Lindsay, 1947 July 10; Typescript (carbon copy). (Box 8)
      - Untitled, by Lindsay, 1947 June 23 and 26; Typescript. (Box 8)
  - France, "The Monnet Four-Year Plan for the French Economy," report of the State Department, Office of Ingelligence Research, 1947 February 28; Hectographed copy. (Box 9)
  - House Select Committee on Foreign Aid (Herter Committee) (Box 9)
    - "Country Section of Final Report," by Lindsay, Herter Committee report, 1948 March 4; Typescript (carbon copy). (Box 9)
    - "Draft of Thoughts on the Major Problems of the Marshall Proposals," memoranda for the staff of the Herter Committee, undated; Mimeographed copies. (Box 9)
    - "The European Recovery Program: Dollar Needs and Dollar Resources," memorandum on Herter Committee stationary, undated; Mimeographed copy. (Box 9)
    - "Memorandum for Congressman Herter," suggestions about labor leaders in ERP and resumes, 1948 February 6; Typescript copies. (Box 9)
    - "The Place of the United States in European Industrial Development," by Lindsay, memorandum for Herter Committee, 1948 April 10; Typescript and printed copies. (Box 9)
    - "Preliminary Report of the House Select Committee on Foreign Aid," resolution, 1947 November 4; Printed and mimeographed copies. (Box 9)
  - International Reconstruction Organization, proposal by J. F. Zwicky, 1947 June 16; Typescript. (Box 9)
  - Italy, correspondence and reports concrning post-war economic situation, Typescript and hectographed copies. (Box 9)
  - Netherlands (Box 9)
    - "Answers to Questions of the Select Committee on Foreign Aid," report of the American Embassy, The Hague, and the Netherlands Ministry of Economic Affairs, 1947 September; Mimeographed copy. (Box 9)
    - "The Benelux Agreement," by Lindsay, memorandum to the Herter Committee, 1948 February 20; Two typescript drafts (carbon copies). (Box 9)
    - "The Benelux Customs Convention between the Belgo-Luxembourg Economic Union and the Netherlands," report of the American Embassy in Brussels, 1947 August 11; Hectographed copy. (Box 9)
    - "Memorandum on the Foreign Exchange Position (of the Netherlands)," report of the Minister of Finance, The Hague, 1947 April 23; Mimeographed copy. (Box 9)
    - "The Netherlands After the War," memorandum, 1947 September 17; Mimeographed copy. (Box 9)
    - "Netherlands Trade with Germany," report of the Netherlands Trust Company, 1947 October; Typescript (carbon copy). (Box 9)
    - "Notes Taken at the Meeting Held at Baron von Boetzelaer's Residence," memorandum for Herter Committee, 1947 September 17; Mimeographed copy. (Box 9)
    - Possible exports from the Netherlands to the United States, correspondence between Herter Committee and the Netherlands Ministry of Economic Affairs, 1947 October; Typescripts. (Box 9)
  - Soviet Union, "Soviet Fulfillment of the Fourth Five-Year Plan in 1946 and Prospects for 1947," report of the State Department, Office of Intelligence Research, 1947 May 26; Mimeographed copy. (Box 9)
  - Trieste, "Sea and Rail Traffic Through Trieste in 1947," memorandum from Leonard Unger to J. J. Kaplan, undated; Hectographed copy. (Box 9)
  - United Nations (Box 9)
    - Memoranda relating to the Atomic Energy Commission report, 1947 January; Typescript (carbon copies). (Box 9)
    - Memoranda relating to the Military Staff Committee, 1947 May-June; Mimeographed copies. (Box 9)
  - Yugoslavia (Box 9)
    - "Conversation in Dubrovnik," by Lindsay, memorandum concerning partisan operations in World War II, 1976 October 5; Typescript (photocopy). (Box 9)
    - "Developments in Yugoslavia, March-August 1945," by Lindsay, report, 1946 September; Typescript (carbon copy). (Box 9)
- 1982 Increment (Box 10)
  - President's Task Force on Government Organization, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Working papers, 1967 June (Box 10)
    - Final reports, 1967 September (Box 10)
    - Final report, 1967 October (Box 10)
  - Richard M. Nixon presidential transition memoranda (Box 10)
    - Preparing for the post-election transition, August, 1968 October (Box 10)
    - National security, 1968 November (Box 10)
    - Staffing the White House, 1968 November (Box 10)
    - Executive Branch organization, 1968 December (Box 10)
- 1992 Increment (Box 10)
  - Eisenhower's United States Presidential Campaign schedules, 1952 (Box 10)
- 1993 Increment (Box 11-16)
  - Beacons in the Night research materials (Box 11-15)
    Relates to British and American operations in Yugoslavia in 1944-1945, including photocopies and notes.
  - Beacons in the Night oversize research materials (Box 16)
- 2010 Increment (Box 17-18)
  - Subject Files (Box 17)
    - "Covert Activities," by Richard M. Bissell, Jr., memorandum containing policy recommendations on this topic, addressed to Franklin Lindsay and Roger Fisher, 1968 September 17; Typescript. (Box 17)
    - United Nations Atomic Energy Commission, reference material (Box 17)
    - Yugoslavia (Box 17)
      - Declassified U.S. government documents, 1945-1947; Photocopies. (Box 17)
      - Yugoslav-American Conference, Dubrovnik, 1976 (Box 17)
  - Seminars and Study Groups (Box 17)
    - National Planning Association, Committee on Security through Arms Control, 1958 (Box 17)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, Discussion Group on Political Aspects of Unconventional Warfare, 1962 (Box 17)
    - Harvard-M.I.T. Arms Control Seminar, 1961-1968 (Box 17)
      - List of participants, 1961-1968 (Box 17)
      - Memoranda, minutes, and reports (Box 17)
        - 1961 (Box 17)
        - 1962-1963 (Box 17)
        - 1963-1964 (Box 17)
        - 1964-1965 (Box 17)
        - 1965-1966 (Box 17)
        - 1967-1968 (Box 17)
    - Cambridge Discussion Group (on Vietnam War), 1966 (Box 17)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, Discussion Group on Intelligence and Foreign Policy, 1967 (Box 17)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, Discussion Group on Intelligence and Foreign Policy, 1968 (Box 17)
    - Bermuda Vietnam Memorandum (Carnegie Endowment for International Peace), 1968 (Box 17)
    - Richard M. Nixon presidential transition (Box 17)
      - Task forces, various, 1968 (Box 17)
      - Task Force on Organization of the Executive Branch, 1968 (Box 17)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace-Brookings Institution, Strategic Arms Policy Study Group, 1969 (Box 17)
    - Intelligence Study Group, Institute of Politics, Harvard University, 1975-1976 (Box 18)
      - Correspondence (Box 18)
      - Draft report (Box 18)
      - Memoranda (Box 18)
      - Meeting minutes (Box 18)
      - Notes (Box 18)
      - Participant lists (Box 18)
      - Reference material (Box 18)
    - National Academy of Sciences, Panel on the Impact of National Security Controls On International Technology Transfer, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Speeches and Writings (Box 18)
    - Unconventional Warfare, Foreign Affairs, 1962 January (Box 18)
    - "A Possible Nuclear Alternate to the Plutonium Breeder Reactor,", 1976; Typescript. (Box 18)
    - "From Partisans to Contras: Revolutions and Foreign Interventions," draft, 1988; Typescript (two files). (Box 18)
    - Kiev talk, 1991 May 22 (Box 18)
    - "Soviet Enterprises Will Need Help in Adapting to a Market Environment,", 1991 August 26 (Box 18)
    - "Defense Conversion in the United States,", 1991 November 27 (Box 18)
    - "Echoes of Hitler in Milosevic's Suppression in Kosovo," Boston Globe, 1998 June 26 (Box 18)
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1943-1961
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - 2010 release of records, 1945
    Available as PDF files. Arranged chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2015 November release of records, 1944-1946 (Box 18)
    Includes memoranda, messages, meeting minutes, and reports regarding military operations in Yugoslavia (1944-1945) as well as an outline of a War Department study on atomic policy (circa 1946).
  - 2018 release of records, 1943-1961